<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Cloud.Virt.AI.Sec</title>
        <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Cloud.Virt.AI.Sec</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><managingEditor>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Your 24/7 Veeam AI Expert: How Veeam Intelligence Revolutionizes Backup Management Support</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/your-24-7-veeam-ai-expert/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/your-24-7-veeam-ai-expert/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-new-era-of-intelligent-data-protectionunveiling-the-powerful-capabilities-of-veeam-intelligence">A New Era of Intelligent Data Protection—Unveiling the Powerful Capabilities of Veeam Intelligence</h2>
<h3 id="introduction-the-painful-experience-of-late-night-documentation-searches">Introduction: The Painful Experience of Late-Night Documentation Searches</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s 2 AM. Your backup job has failed again.</p>
<p>The screen displays the error &ldquo;Failed to create snapshot&rdquo; and your mind goes blank. If you&rsquo;re a Veeam administrator, you&rsquo;ve been here before.</p>
<p>The familiar troubleshooting marathon begins:</p>
<ol>
<li>Google the error code → 30 minutes gone</li>
<li>Search through Veeam documentation → Another 45 minutes wasted</li>
<li>Ask for help in WeChat groups → Wait for responses</li>
<li>Open a technical support ticket → Queue for hours</li>
</ol>
<p>Six hours later, you finally solve it. A simple permission configuration issue.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Zero-Cost Physical Air Gap: How Veeam Outperforms Million-Dollar Sheltered Harbor Solutions</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/veeam-airgap-backup-step-by-step/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/veeam-airgap-backup-step-by-step/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="zero-cost-physical-air-gap-how-veeam-outperforms-million-dollar-sheltered-harbor-solutions">Zero-Cost Physical Air Gap: How Veeam Outperforms Million-Dollar Sheltered Harbor Solutions</h1>
<p>First, I must thank my colleague Zhang Yuan. The design concept for this solution actually originated from his idea of automatically controlling network firewalls through Palo Alto devices, which he shared internally several years ago. This article simply reproduces his excellent design using zero-cost OpenWRT.</p>
<p>Remember that 2019 article about ransomware attacks?</p>
<p>At that time, I emphasized the importance of data isolation. Ransomware is becoming increasingly intelligent—they no longer just encrypt production data, but also destroy backup servers, delete backup catalogs, and even attack dedicated storage devices.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AI Reshaping Data Protection (Part 2): Using Claude Code to Control Your VBR Server</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/AI-Reshapes-Data-Protection-02/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/AI-Reshapes-Data-Protection-02/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="ai-reshaping-data-protection-part-2-using-claude-code-to-control-your-vbr-server">AI Reshaping Data Protection (Part 2): Using Claude Code to Control Your VBR Server</h1>
<p>In our previous article, we set up an AI terminal environment with Claude Code + GLM-4.6. Today, I want to show you a revolutionary way of working: <strong>zero-code</strong> control of your Veeam Backup &amp; Replication server through Veeam RestAPI. Don&rsquo;t be intimidated by terms like API - in today&rsquo;s content, you won&rsquo;t need to write a single line of code to make Claude Code (hereafter CC) your VBR operations assistant! Let CC bring you a completely different data protection experience.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AI Reshapes Data Protection (Part 1): Claude Code &#43; GLM-4.6 in Practice, Building AI CLI Tools from Scratch</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/AI-Reshapes-Data-Protection-01/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/AI-Reshapes-Data-Protection-01/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="ai-reshapes-data-protection-part-1-claude-code--glm-46-in-practice-building-ai-cli-tools-from-scratch">AI Reshapes Data Protection (Part 1): Claude Code + GLM-4.6 in Practice, Building AI CLI Tools from Scratch</h1>
<p>Vibe coding has been incredibly popular lately, with Claude Code and Codex competing fiercely. I&rsquo;m grateful for these excellent AI tools that bring entirely new capabilities and perspectives to our data protection and security industry. Starting with this series, I want to share how these AI tools can provide different capabilities for our data protection workflows, giving you an up-close look at the changes AI is bringing to our industry.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Free YARA Rules for Veeam - A Practical Guide to Ransomware.live Integration</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/veeam13-security-features-03/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/veeam13-security-features-03/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In our previous articles, we introduced how Veeam v13 continues to enhance its YARA malware scanning capabilities. However, the limitation of official rule sets is a very real challenge. There aren&rsquo;t many free YARA rule sources available online, and high-quality ones are even scarcer. Today, I want to introduce you to a hidden gem: Ransomware.live - a professional open-source ransomware threat intelligence platform that provides free YARA rules for 62 major ransomware gangs, making it a perfect complement to Veeam&rsquo;s YARA scanning functionality.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>V13 Malware Detection Comprehensive Upgrade: Practical Evolution from Passive Protection to Active Response</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/veeam13-security-features-02/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/11/veeam13-security-features-02/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In version v13, malware detection capabilities have achieved a significant leap forward. Compared to the real-time detection capabilities already available in the v12 era, v13 has brought qualitative improvements in threat response mechanisms, platform coverage, and intelligence levels. In my previous articles, I&rsquo;ve detailed the ransomware attack detection principles and configuration methods for v12. Today, building on that foundation, let&rsquo;s explore the key upgrades that v13 brings.</p>
<h2 id="v12-detection-capabilities-review-the-separation-of-detection-and-response">v12 Detection Capabilities Review: The Separation of Detection and Response</h2>
<p>In the v12 era, Veeam&rsquo;s malware detection primarily relied on two mechanisms:</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Making VBR Login More Secure: A Complete Guide to v13 SAML &#43; Azure EntraID Integration</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam13-security-features-01/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam13-security-features-01/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2025/09/veeam13-security-features-01/featured-image.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>In version v13, the most significant new features focus on enhanced security capabilities. Starting with this article, I&rsquo;ll provide a detailed walkthrough of the new security features introduced in v13 through practical applications.</p>
<p>Today, let&rsquo;s start with authentication. In enterprise-level backup architectures, the security of management console accounts and access governance is critically important. Veeam Backup &amp; Replication (VBR) now supports SAML-based Single Sign-On (SSO) in v13, which means you can centralize authentication to your organization&rsquo;s existing Identity Provider (IdP) — such as Azure EntraID. Through SAML integration, you can unify the management of VBR login with your company&rsquo;s account lifecycle, group policies, MFA, and auditing: operations become clearer, permission revocation is more timely, and you achieve higher compliance. This article uses Azure EntraID as an example to demonstrate this integration in detail. For other similar solutions like Authing in China or international options like Okta and Auth0, you can follow the Azure methods to try them out.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>In-Depth Analysis: Veeam V13 Release Strategy and Deployment Options</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam-software-appliance-06/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam-software-appliance-06/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Veeam&rsquo;s Chief Product Officer Anton Gostev published an FAQ on the <a href="https://forums.veeam.com/veeam-backup-replication-f2/frequently-asked-questions-release-schedule-and-deployment-options-t99995.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">R&amp;D forums</a> that clearly explains V13&rsquo;s release schedule, deployment options, licensing, and migration strategy. For customers and partner engineers, this isn&rsquo;t just &ldquo;news&rdquo; – it&rsquo;s a practical guide that will influence decisions about &ldquo;whether to upgrade immediately and how to plan migration paths.&rdquo; This article uses that post as a starting point, combining it with official release information to analyze its actual impact on users of different scales, and provides actionable recommendations.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Let Veeam Handle the Complexity: A Hands-On Guide to Infrastructure Appliance</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam-software-appliance-05/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam-software-appliance-05/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In Veeam v13, not only did they make the backup server into a pre-hardened Software Appliance, but they also introduced the <strong>Veeam Infrastructure Appliance</strong> specifically designed to host role services. If the Software Appliance is the &ldquo;command center,&rdquo; then the Infrastructure Appliance is more like a pre-configured, ready-to-use &ldquo;execution unit&rdquo;: it provides a unified, controlled, and compliant operating environment for roles like Proxy, Mount Server, and Hardened Repository.</p>
<h2 id="1-why-choose-infrastructure-appliance">1. Why Choose Infrastructure Appliance</h2>
<p>The reasons for choosing Infrastructure Appliance can be summarized in three points: <strong>fast, simple, secure</strong>. Veeam&rsquo;s JeOS (Just enough OS) image built on Rocky 9 packages the operating system and runtime dependencies into a controlled, minimal distribution unit. When you deploy an Infrastructure Appliance, you&rsquo;re essentially getting a Linux server optimized for backup roles according to best practices that&rsquo;s ready to use out of the box.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Making Veeam Updates Both Secure and Fast: A Complete Guide to Building Local Update Repository Servers</title>
    <link>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam-software-appliance-04/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Coku2015@gmail.com (Lei Wei)</author>
    <guid>https://blog.backupnext.cloud/en/2025/09/veeam-software-appliance-04/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In the previous articles of this series, we&rsquo;ve installed and run the Veeam Software Appliance, experiencing its &ldquo;secure by default&rdquo; management approach. Now, let&rsquo;s tackle a question many people genuinely care about: <strong>How to enable Veeam Software Appliance to automatically receive updates in an offline environment, just like it would online</strong>. The official documentation mentions specifying a local mirror repository, but it doesn&rsquo;t provide detailed instructions on how to build, sync, or configure certificates. Based on my lab testing, I&rsquo;ll walk you through the complete process step by step.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
